

GANESH VISWESWARAN

RISK CONSULTANT/BUSINESS ANALYST/DATA ANALYST - BANKING

Techno Functional Specialist to drive/maximise service value for your Business Products & Processes with Minimal Risk.

PROFILE

16+ Years of techno functional experience in Credit risk Reporting, Commercial Banking and IT Operations Domain playing roles across Risk Analytics, governance, Data Analytics, Project Management and Automation.

Best placed in roles to create and enhance products/processes to provide maximum delivery with minimum risks by adequate controls.

CONTACT

PHONE: +91-9704164915

WEBSITE:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ganeshvis weswaran

EMAIL: ganesh.hariraj@gmail.com

HOBBIES

Carnatic Music – Vocal Books – Epic Fantasy Playing Veena

EDUCATION

DCAM v2.2 (Data Management Capability Assessment Model) Certified 2023

PGDBA, Operations - Symbiosis Centre for Distance Learning, Pune 2010 - 2012

B.Tech (EEE), Sastra University, Tanjore 2002 – 2007

Business English Certification (BEC), Vantage, Cambridge

WORK EXPERIENCE

Standard Chartered Global Business Services, Aug2017-ToDate

Assistant Vice President, Capital Reporting

- \$166 Audit Stakeholder for Capital Reporting Operation Risk Controls, RWA Calculations and RWA Manual Adjustments
- ✓ Basel IV Implementation Lead for User Acceptance Testing (UAT) for HK, CN, SG, TW, UK Credit risk treatment and Reporting (Ongoing)

Senior Manager - Capital Reporting

- Lead, Data Quality, Governance and Control 6 Members Established new operating model which includes. Data Profiling & Monitoring (Informatica DQ) DQ Issues record, Escalation, and change prioritization Data Quality Management Forum – Monthly BCBS239 Compliance Review and Tracking Audit Open Actions – Track and remediate.
- ✓ Lead, RWA Analytics 7 Members Credit Risk Treatment (RWA) Treatment Subject Matter Expert
 Payious and Attest Production Compliance Register (PR

Review and Attest Prudential Compliance Register (PRA) Front End Team for all Audit Queries (Internal/External) and Internal bank stakeholders Consultant for RWA optimization initiatives

Signoff Stakeholder for all Credit Risk Change Requirements

Manager - Capital Reporting

- ✓ Team Member of RWA Analytics Team
- ✓ Consultant on Credit risk Treatment for Regulatory Reporting
- ✓ Credit Risk Queries Management for Internal/External Audit

Intellect Design Arena, Product Consultant – Corporate Banking Dec 2015–Aug 2017

Business Analyst for Front End Corporate Users and Bank End Staff Products which includes Account Management, Payments, Collections, Liquidity and Supply Chain Finance

HSBC GLT, Senior Business Analyst – Commercial Banking Sep2010–Dec2015

Business Analyst for Front End Corporate Users and Bank End Staff Products which includes Account Management and Payments

Keane India Limited, Senior Software Engineer

Dec2007-Sep2010

BMC Patrol Monitoring - Part of IT Operations
Hand on Windows, Linux, and Unix - VB Scripting and Perl scripting

SKILLS

